Chih-Yen Chang 張芝嫣

979-739-0776 - cychihyen@gmail.com

PROFILE

A highly motivated and experienced web developer and software engineer. Strongly focused and knowledgeable full-stack website design with a wide breadth of software installation and maintenance knowledge. Proficient in designing, coding, testing, and maintaining website functions. Great communicator of complex technological concepts between professional and non-professional audiences.

OBJECTIVE

Look forward to explore a different aspect of software development and help the company or business in creating a better service, user interactions and experiences.

EDUCATION

Computer Science: Texas A&M University, College Station, Texas

Bachelor of Science, College of Engieering, Minor in Business, Overall GPA: 3.41

2011 - 2015

SKILLS

C++, C, Java, Python, JavaScript, AJAX, HTML, CSS, Rails, Ruby, PHP, MySQL, Haskell, Latex, JQuery, Agile/SCRUM, Github, SaaS, BDD, TDD

LANGUAGES

Mandarin Chinese, Taiwanese, English

WORK EXPERIENCE

Beauty of Sharing Web Developer Foundation

2016 - 2017

Redesign the website with administration and membership system in multilanguages using mainly PHP, MySQL, AJAX, JavaScript, and HTML/CSS. Working with graphic designers to develop a brand new front-end design. Configure the MySQL server system. Create, test, and maintains databases and tables. Retrieve and sort data to display on the site.

Foundation 2015

Beauty of Sharing Project Manager Intern

Manage a website project to build a web platform to help local communities, schools and organizations to host events and take applications online. Main responsibility is to coordinate with clients and team members for better website UI design and development using HTML/CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap.

Department of Computer Science and Engineering 2014 - 2016

Peer Teacher

Work with teaching assistants to tutor an average of 20 college students in programming languages including C++ and C.

IN-CLASS PROJECTS

Museum of American G.I. Online Survey 2015

Develop an online survey system to allow visitor to register in the system and allow museum staffs to generate and visualize visitor's summary statistics that will help them apply for funding. Using Ruby on Rails, MySQL, automated testing, ERB, SCSS. Provide assistance and support issues related to database system and queries.

VoiceSketch

2015

Build an online learning system with ability to record handwriting and voice at the same time. Add recording ability with play/pause, replay feature that provide a

better communication and teaching tool between teachers and students. Built by

using JavaScript, HTML, CSS.

Ambient Story

2015

Web storyteller that increases immersion by changing ambient qualities of story as

it prints using JavaScript, HTML, CSS.

Food Hunter

2015

Web application that recommends recipes by user-inputted ingredients using

Python, JSON, HTML, CSS.

HACKATHON PROJECTS

Kalendar TAMUHACK 2015 Time management web application that tracks to-do list and schedules tasks on

calendar using Python, HTML, CSS, and Google Calendar API

Runmania

An Android app that makes jogging more fun and enjoyable by introducing games

Houston Hackathon 2015 and competitions between users. Using Java and Google Map API.

Epiphany Trip

Hackdfw 2014

Android app that suggests destinations by start location, travel time, and weather

in seconds using Java and Weather underground API.

Worth the Trip

TAMUHack 2014

Web application that generates road trip routes by recommending nearby

attractions to users using JavaScript, Google Map API, SendGrid, and Bootstrap.

Won best use of Google API.

ORGANIZATIONS

Taiwanese Student Association

2015-2016

Vice President

Assist the President with event planning/hosting and coordinate between officers,

schools, and members.

Stand Manager at Football Concession

Assign tasks to other student workers and check beginning and ending inventories.

Aggie Women in Computer Science (AWICS)

2014 - 2016

Member

Attend meetings held by AWICS and volunteer at organizational events.

Society of Asian

Scientists &

Engineers (SASE)

2013 - 2014

Member

Attend meetings held by SASE and volunteer at organizational events.